Today I want to talk about a
topic I find so
interesting, and I think that maybe, maybe,
between Saint (for you too,
who's called Open)
and me (my name is Lars, and I work
in a startup called Layer
Tree), we're making an educational platform
in the world of crypto. We work
with a few different companies
in the crypto world, like blockchain,
etc., but we're still a small
startup, and as you're in a small
startup, there often aren't too
many
developers. There were two of us, there are
still two of us: me and Tristan.
At the beginning, we thought, OK,
our product is a website, and there are only
two of us, we don't want to
spend too much time configuring
the infrastructure, etc. So we chose
a service for
server hosting and for the database. We
chose a service like Carousel,
and it was really great at the
beginning. We didn't have any problems
with it at all; we were able to work only
with the features and
things that mattered. But after a while,
we started  First, there were problems with
the infrastructure, and because of that, the site
was slow. We had issues with its
slowness
because we had more users, etc.
And
when we had problems like that,
often when we had a tweet that went
viral and caused a surge in traffic, less so for
Tristan, we stopped working and
tried to find a solution because it's
important. If nothing works,
okay, we found a solution, but then
we told the team, "Okay, it's fine, we
found a solution," we paid a little
more for the server, or we found
something else that we thought might
help. But in reality, we didn't have
an overall view, and each time we
had new problems a
few days later, and it continued like that for
weeks, months,
and we spent more and more time on
the infrastructure and not on the
real functionalities.
It wasn't ideal. So I took a step back
and thought, "Okay, I want to
find a solution once and for
all," and that's how I asked myself
the question: how to
identify and solve
infrastructure problems with a small team and limited
resources.  And
I think this might be useful for you
too, I hope, even if you're in a
small team or a large
company. So that's what I'm going to
talk about tonight.
When I started doing some research
in the performance world, I realized
that in large companies, you
have people who work exclusively with website
performance,
and it's called See Site.
I found an article by an
SRE who talked about it; it was a really good
article for me.
[Music]
He wrote about systems
and what we do with
monitoring
and observing. Everyone told me that's
monitoring,
and with that, you can solve
problems.
Okay, what exactly is observing?
[Music]
And
observability is whether you can
understand what's happening in a
system using only its
external outputs.
It means, like us,
can you understand what's happening in the
boxes here using only the
CPUs or a few logs?
And for us, we had really bad
observability, and that's why...
It was impossible to know
how to solve problems, so the
question is how can we shed
light on
the system, how can we improve
observability?
And for that, we have
[Music]
something called
telemetry.
We often talk about logs,
and
your goal is for your
infrastructure and your code to emit
telemetry. That's what the Blues thing is
here.
And if you do that,
you
'll see the power to see what's
happening in your system.
With telemetry, there are hundreds
of tools, etc.,
that you can use to read that.
But the problem now is that it's
not necessarily easy to
implement. There were only
two of us, and we didn't have much
time. It wasn't always
easy to
implement telemetry or anything like that.
But it's good news now. There's
a new standard
that was built for 2029, but it's only now that it's
really starting to be
usable. It's called Open,
and it's a standard that virtually
all companies in the world are
observing.  Summer is
using, or starting to use,
now, and that means it's going to be
possible
for us developers to
really use telemetry and
observability without too much work,
and that's really cool. Okay,
now I want to show you
how you can do that.
I'm going to show you how before you
ran your application with Note Server
simply, and you're going to add a little
bit of magic.
It's just a file and an argument
there, and you activate your application
with that, and it's going to change your life.
So this is a daemon. By the way, I
'm
Norwegian originally, and
I've been here in Paris for six months, and we've already had
three strikes, I think, and
sometimes we have problems with the
trains. So for the daemon, I recreated the
SNCF website
because I think maybe it can
inspire them to optimize the system a bit. It's
quite simple; there are five buttons here that
work well. They correspond to five
different things.
Okay, that's it.
Imagine that you were the one who made the
website, and after some time,
there are problems where
the  The site is running slowly, or
maybe it's the rush, maybe it's
a dream, or something, I do
n't know,
and you don't know exactly where the
problem is. Is it the
database? Is it my code? It's
never my code, no. Is it
something else? In a
large company, it could be several
teams, it could be even more difficult.
So now I can show you
how to add a file.
You have your application, and you have a
file. Now you add this,
which is called tracing.
And here it's not too complicated.
First, we
define a gold job
with a service name, SNCF web, OK.
And after that, we do something that I
find really magical. The way it
works here is GetNote Halloween.
It will automatically add
or slightly modify the code. It
works with about 50 libraries in the
nodes, like system threads and HTTP
Expressia, etc., automatically. So your
code will automatically generate the traces,
and
we also add a Prisma plugin.
After that,
you define where we want to send the
data because  It's a standard, and that's
the beauty of it—you can
change it whenever you want. I really like
Data Dog, so I read that, but you
can switch to Lightster for Unicorn. It's
simple: you don't have Wonder
Looking,
and that's cool. Okay, we're going to run
the application with an argument here, and
that argument means it
runs the tracing before the server, and that way
it can inject the codes, etc.
Okay, and we continue,
and the users click a little,
click-click,
that's good.
And now
[Music]
we can go
to Data Dog, and I hope my love will
work. I think so. And here you see
all the requests, which you can see
in,
and that's automatic. We didn't do it that way; that's the
automatic tracing.
And here we can see,
for example, "get your,"
and we can see the flame graft, and that's exactly
what's
happening. It's middleware here, and
Prisma is a flow curry, and we
can see exactly the
SQL, and that way you can
really filter and find the
ghouls.  to be captivating and we
want to find the N-point which is with
the problems so I created an old one
here where we see our 5 and point and the
four here are quite fast but we have
the RER it's always the RER
[Laughter] it's
not good for us okay
we'll see a bit here we can find
the flame anyway
and here we see the RER flame
and we have a bit here which is
150 ml which is an
fs5 okay second thing we have a
[Music]
which is fast okay that's good a third
is a database curry which
is too slow okay three things okay we can
go see in our code if we can
find the 3 things and we find the
n-point the RER here
and we see
okay
we have the three things the first thing
which is actually a readfight
of a file called
upcoming stripes
okay we can see
this file
okay this file is a sense file
again
this is really a bit big so to
improve we can  Find another
file that's a bit smaller, or
we're not really using this
list here, so we'll keep it simple.
Why not? Okay, the second
thing was fast, so we don't
need to do the same thing here. And the
third was the curry
here, and
that was too slow. We had this
problem
several times,
and I'm guessing it's a missing index in
the database. Okay, we
see we're currying the name, so it's a
process. I don't know if you're
familiar with this, but I use an
application to see this. It's the
database
index of the name,
so I'm adding a name index here. Save. Okay,
now I hope it's going to be
better. Okay, I'm restarting
the application,
and we're going to
click a bit more,
especially on the RSI.
That's going to be better.
Okay,
wait here, and I think it's going to
appear
here. And besides,
with
all the other applications that have an
observer call, Belletti Fronton, there are
many features. You can
do sports dashes
and all that, and
[Music].
I think we can try that. Yes, here we
see and  The RER (suburban train) was slow, and now
we see that it's really fast, even more so, like
sales, say 20 milliseconds.
And the flame charge
shows that too, so great, we solved
the problem thanks to the "
yes"
and that's what we did with the cold air
too.
[Music]
And now we don't have any more problems.
If we have problems, if something does
n't work or there are errors, we can
easily find and solve them, and
spend time on things that
matter in a startup.
That was all. If you have any
questions, I'm here for that.